hi everyone
yep good everyone so this is Jay from
1237 Ventures and once again we would I
would like to welcome everyone who
joined in this webinar sessions okay
innovating the future of insurance
aligning with the launch of FWD style
Studio accelerator called five powered
by FWD insurance with the collaborations
of Contrition several managers all right
so without further adoles we would like
to invite our speaker or of the day mark
a head of incubation's hub for FWD
insurance so women will be sharing with
us on the overview of FWD Malaysia
strategy and strategic Direction and
plan Innovation culture within the group
and definitely uh the demand or the
emergent emerging Trend in the
international industry so just a little
bit intro of uh Mark so much has
significant Innovation and
transformation experience in supporting
government private sector as well as
International Organization at the
highest level across Europe Asia Africa
and Middle East
so he is currently the head of
incubation hit at FWD group
appendations insurer and at the same
time he is also holding a role as a
members of International Association of
facilitators so definitely he's still
set include
um corporate Innovation public policies
program management Communications and
investor relations so yep so before that
uh throughout the session if you have
any questions uh to avoid interactions
so please feel free to drop it in the
chat box and we will be addressing uh at
the end of the sessions okay yeah so
passing to you mark
thanks tree
yeah welcome everybody to today's
webinar we're excited to have you give
me a second and I'll share my screen
I don't have a lot of slides to talk
about recovering briefly and I just
wanted to cover you know the the sign up
Studio initiative the concept and who we
are at FWD insurance
that's the B group we're a pan-Asian
insurance company we're present around
10 markets and countries uh across Asia
and this includes obviously Malaysia but
we're also present throughout most of
Southeast Asia Japan Hong Kong and the
Philippines as well these are just some
of the statistics but we have over 10
million customers across Asia we're
relatively new company this is our 10th
year of operations and there's a big
push right in terms of changing the way
that people think about insurance that's
our vision and there's a lot of demand
internally there's a lot of initiatives
in turn need to try new things to change
the way that we operate and try and do
things a little bit differently from the
way the insurance has traditionally been
operating around the world
some of our key objectives as I said
before our vision is about changing the
way people feel about insurance we want
to make products easier and simpler to
understand for the customers we want the
customer experience to be simpler more
seamless from the purchase Journey
throughout throughout claim servicing
for example we want to have a flexible
organization right with discipline
execution and what you will see the
outcome of a lot of these initiatives is
that the customer experience has a very
strong Focus it's all about being
customer-led we are big in the digital
space a lot of the work that we do is
with an eye towards future technology
future products future ways of working
and that's a large reason why we started
the startup Studio initiative which I'll
cover in a little bit more but the main
idea behind this is that we fully
believe right about in our vision of
changing the way that people feel by
insurance and if you boil it down to the
basics that's what the setup ecosystem
is doing each of you in this space is
about changing the way that people have
traditionally viewed fintech industry
the ensure tech industry and every other
industry right and our objective behind
startup studio is about collaborating
with startups understanding new ways of
working and potentially collaborating
you as well as investing to you
so startup Studio it started here in
Malaysia in
2021 about two and a half years ago and
we have two main tracks here the first
is a pre-acelator that we ran in 2021 in
2022 we ran four cohorts to identify in
Groom high potential startups we also
published the insure Tech opportunity
reports in 21 and last year and we had a
number of events workshops
collaborations to be able to develop the
ecosystem startup ecosystem
in parallel with that we have set up a
venture capital fund same Ventures this
one operational in November last year
and the objective here is to identify
and invest into
lead C Series a insure Tech and fintech
companies with the goal of again
identifying startups that have great
potential to support our businesses grow
them and if they want to expand we have
a ready-made Network process I said 10
different countries and markets across
Asia
a little bit more about the setup Studio
you will see some of the names of the
startups that participated some of you
are also present in today's
webinar it's really about
identifying startups the original focus
in 2021 and 2022 was actually focused in
Malaysia and we've pivoted since in 2023
towards cohort 5 and what we call phase
two where we're expanding our our reach
outside of Malaysia we're looking for
startups who are a little bit beyond
just an ideation State Should pivoted
from a pre-accelerator to a full
accelerator and even slightly Beyond it
and I just want to highlight if some of
you have been in or some of you have
experience with or have been in previous
cohorts of startup Studio the format
this year is a little bit different
there is a lot more focus on identifying
startups organizations which already
have ready-made products and it's about
making sure that there's already a
ready-made fit ability to collaborate
with us via FW Tucker full for example
or a new company in Malaysia FW life
that sells uh conventional insurance
it's about
not so much about the traditional you
know classroom learning having a
curriculum in your traditional
accelerators and pre accelerators it's
more by identifying the best startups
that fit our problem statements working
together with them in order to
operationalize test a proof of concept
and hopefully be able to
Implement them fully
uh
Solan from 1337 will also have a couple
of things to share with you after which
we have a question and answer session
sure I would like me to start now Mark
sure go ahead
okay sure uh hi everyone I think I've
spoken to many of you already in the
last few days
um
let me just share some slides
okay so I'm going to tell you a bit
about the program so you heard from Mark
about fwd's Innovation Direction and
um and and in the previous cohorts so
yeah I think Mark has already mentioned
this point but I just want to uh mention
it again this accelerator is quite
different from the previous
pre-accelerators the previous
pre-accelerators is where uh people came
to us with an idea they had no business
knowledge usually little business
knowledge and they would put through a
curriculum in which they developed the
idea into a business and then the
business was investable right
so in this accelerator it is more for
later stage startups even in businesses
who want to
um who want to collaborate with FWD
many of them have ready products ready
Solutions and
it's a matter of tailoring them or
applying them to FWD so I've met with
quite a few of you all in the last few
days and it's about uh
it's about ensuring that FWD meets its
objectives and objectives are in terms
of a problem statement and our job at
1337 which is a partner of FWD in this
in running this accelerator our job is
basically to ensure two things number
one is we ensure that you get access to
the right people and number two is that
we expedite things we move we push
things along make sure it happens fast
so it's a Time limited program it's an
eight-week the POC design the proof of
concept design is an eight week period
in this eight week period uh all the
meetings will be attended by 1337
Ventures we will get you the right
people to speak to and then and move
things along you know we will take notes
we'll get the next meeting and the next
meeting and the next meeting until
you've completed your POC design and
then you can then go on to implement it
with FWD so let me just talk a bit about
the problem statements because I know
you're curious about that uh drink can
you please put the next slide
okay we have six problem statements
these six problem statements have been
identified by the Tucker for business as
being important to them
um and the purpose of the accelerator is
basically to Source businesses to
address these problems right so let's
start with the first one the first one
is called growth Partnerships and it
reads how might we explore Partnerships
or Avenues to gain access to existing
customer base allowing us to expand our
reach and serve a wider audience
effectively so this is about how FWD can
form Partnerships to grow their business
right so just to give you uh uh just
just to make up an example let's say
your lifestyle app lifestyle app with
hundreds of thousands of users maybe FWD
can form a collaboration with you where
you have some kind of referrals
referrals agreement with them where you
promote or you package some some of
their products with some of your
products and promote it on your platform
and in that Way Drive business for FWD
as well as sharing the benefit of that
new business lab so that's the first
problem statement going on to the second
problem statement
thank you
is so the second one is on customer
experience so this one reads how might
we reduce friction for customers during
the onboarding process and improve their
buying experience by streamlining and
simplifying the steps required to
purchase insurance products so
um
what comes to mind let me think
improving the buying experience so uh
reducing friction okay nothing comes to
mind at the moment for this one let's go
on to the next one but basically
anything to improve onboarding improving
the buying experience simplifying the
steps required to purchase insurance
okay maybe an example for this one would
be
um
insurance aggregators if you're an
aggregator
promoting fwd's products will simplify
if you have a a a an Avenue for them to
purchase it on on your system and
simplify the process for purchasing it
that that's an option
uh maybe you've gone to the next one
product education so for this one for
example uh so this one reads how might
we use personalized approaches and
Health Data integration to educate
customers about insurance products
during the onboarding process ensuring
that they make informed decisions based
on their unique needs so let's say
you're let's say you're a health
platform and you conduct a survey on a
person's health and you see you find out
that they have high cholesterol then
that would be a good opportunity for for
FWD to promote their critical illness
package so basically
um
that's what so it's a personalized
approach and it enables them to make
informed decisions based on their unique
needs there's a unique need that they
have and they can make an informed
decision by by us promoting that product
to them the right product to Daimler so
that's the third problem statement
let's go to a fourth
so the fourth is about increasing
lifetime value it's about how may we
strategically upsell across cell
relevant Insurance products to existing
customers providing them with
comprehensive coverage while increasing
Customer Loyalty so an example for this
one is basically
um
basically an example of this one is
loyalty and rewards let's say you have a
loyalty program or a Rewards program
then that could potentially be a way to
upsell or cross-sell products to to them
um to to to the customers
and next one please
Financial inclusion so this one is
specifically about payments methods so
recurring payments especially uh to
cater to the needs of underserved
segment during onboarding process and
subsequently enhancing the accessibility
to Insurance products so for this one an
example might be say a gig platform
where we have
you have uh or maybe any sort of b40
platform where they are making regular
payments of some sort and you can
Channel some of the payments into the
insurance payments uh through the
platform
and basically in that way you know
enhance the accessibility to Insurance
products uh maybe or maybe if they if
there's a system where
um like Village heads collect um
collect money from you and they deposit
it because you're unbanked uh that's
that's another example any sort of
financial inclusion
program system uh that will make it
easier to collect payments from
underserved segments right
and last one
so the last one is on process
optimization and this one is
specifically about the claims process
right how might we optimize and expedite
the claims process to enhance customer
satisfaction and ensure a smooth and
efficient experience when customers need
to make a claim
so an obvious example is claims
management platforms other things could
include claims documentation anything to
do with claims maybe AI chatbot where
you can
talk to talk to FWD about making a claim
via AI chatbot anything that that is
that is improving the games process
to enhance customer satisfaction and and
a smooth and efficient experience so
it's basically about CX in the claims
processor
so yeah that that is the six problem
statements so
as I mentioned again some of you uh
earlier stage like uh so there's a
question here about seed stage and above
right so
um seed stage basically it's the
requirement for this program is that
um
the startups or the businesses
participating in this program must be
funded by VC funded basically so it has
to be
um we see funded at a seat stage and
above
um that's that's the requirement a lot
of the startups we have spoken with and
have put in the applications are
actually at a much later stage
um some of them serious B series C some
of them are even listed companies
um and that's fine
um it's just that it's more about what
they have to offer so if if what they
have to offer meets the the problems
that are stated in this solution is is
tailored to the problems that are stated
so some some some some other additional
information is FWD doesn't want to make
any changes any significant changes to
its platform because it's a digital
platform that's been designed uh for the
for its own purpose so it has to be
something modular that can be plugged in
if it's a system and it has to be
something bite-sized low hanging fruit
that they can apply very quickly and
realize the benefits from it easily
so it has to start basic as a proof of
concept and then later in the coming
years you can try to build on it but FWD
will not make changes significant
changes to their systems it has to be
something that's plugged in
um
so that's that's what comes to mind and
um the next slide please
so I just want to talk a bit about the
program so
um I think many of you have already put
in your form uh if not the form is on
the web page and if G you could share
the web page address
um the form is on that web page and
basically after the form is put in we
will conduct a half an hour interview
with you
um Marcus just spoke to you will be on
the interview as well as someone 337
members and basically
um
after that interview if you if you are
accepted to participate in the program
there will be a three-week period known
as office hours office hours is where we
book time of senior people in FWD like
maybe three hours with compliance three
hours with marketing three hours with
the head of life history hours with head
of medical and so on and you have the
opportunity to book a slot with them uh
say a half an hour slot with them and
you can get some of your pressing
questions answered so you're pressing
questions could be you know this is what
we have in mind for the collaboration do
you think it's feasible or do you think
we need to shape it in some way or a
form and basically co-create a model for
a successful partnership in that of
operating in that sorry in that office
hours
uh at the end of the office I was
basically you'll be pitch ready and then
we will have a a a short pitch five ten
minute pitch in which you will uh
convince senior leaders in FWD why you
should go into the proof of concept
design
and then the proof of concept design
will be a eight week
period in that eight week period we will
get you as many or as few meetings as
you want with the right people
um so it's really directed by you who
you want to meet and then we we get the
meeting we so for example if you start
by saying that you want to do a referral
partnership for your lifestyle app right
so the first question you have to ask is
um
uh what product so you might have to
meet with say life life insurance and
you see it then life insurance says yeah
this is a good product but we are
concerned about
um compliance can we
um refer can you refer business to us
when you're not an agency for example
just to give an example so you'll have
to meet with compliance so we will then
get you a meeting with compliance and so
on and so forth so you go through a
period in eight weeks where you get a
series of meetings in which you refine
and you find your proof of concept and
at the end of the eight weeks hopefully
you would have designed your proof of
concept and then you can go on and after
that it's basically
um you will demo the the proof of
concept that means you will get senior
leaders Senior Management and basically
you'll show them hey you know this is
what we've designed and this is what
we're going to go ahead with and then
that that'd be an opportunity for them
to if you really get their buy and then
then they will support you throughout
the whole process of
um executing your POC so let's say for
example you you talk about that that
referrals uh for lifestyle app right so
let's say we decide that we want to run
it for six months and see how it goes
then you I will what you'll do is you'll
identify what success looks like and
then basically you will
um
you will you will run the POC and then
at the end of the POC if the success
criteria has been met you will be
incorporated into business as usual and
then your your collaboration is is
sealed right so that is um
that is uh actually how the program
works so the the in a nutshell your
commitment uh at the moment is basically
10 minutes to fill out the form and half
an hour to do the interview and if you
are selected then basically meetings
will be secured for you as as many or as
few as you did you like and basically
objective is to First work together to
develop that proof of concept so what we
will be trying to ensure is that you are
committed to a positive outcome and
likewise we are committed to a positive
outcome
and um and then it's just basically uh
running in the program
so you haven't put in your form already
please put in your form no yeah I think
we'll just go into q a now so if you
have any questions on FWD and it's
direction for Innovation please raise
them and Mark will address them and if
you have any questions about the program
I'm happy to address them as well sure
so at the end of the program I've
determined under Monday if we decide to
proceed with you yes there will be a
commercial agreement outlining the scope
of the collaboration and the next steps
and so on
yeah it will it will depend on the
nature of the collaboration right so if
you say referrals partnership then it's
a referrals agreement if it's a sort of
like a system introducing a system then
it's some other sort of Engagement uh
kind of a uh an agreement so it really
depends but uh definitely if you're
entering into
uh a collaboration there must be some
kind of legal agreement to make sure
that everyone's risk and rewards are
covered
okay we have another question when does
week one start so we will complete
applications and interviews by the 28
also by the 30th of August and then the
actual program week one starts in
September
starts in September
so the question is will this be a POC uh
Mercy on a ticket or should I take that
yes the POS if they will be on a
commercial basis if there's a if there's
a cost involved that's something that we
can discuss over the course of the
office hours already right we need we
would like to get an indication as well
that being said it's not the expectation
that this is going to be a huge amount
of budget it's about being able to
demonstrate that the hypothesis works
then the idea Works in collaboration FWD
um again we can talk about this model in
the office hours
yeah
so my my definition of POC does not mean
that it's it's not a commercial
Arrangement it just means that you start
with something basic so you're proving
that the concept works you start with
something basic bite-sized
um no hanging fruit and then as you go
on you will increase the the add to it
in the future so POC just means that
start with something basic and you have
certain metrics to qualify and and to go
on and then basically if you meet them
then you go on to the next stage
so next question is FWD also looking for
solution targeted for FWD distribution
Channel agencies and agents yes is the
answer to that right if there is a
potential to improve the way that we
distribute our products happy to look at
it as well
okay
yeah we talk about buying experience as
one of them so it's so it's definitely
relevant to buying experience we talk
about personalization
um upselling cross-selling so these are
things where
for example if you have a customer
relationship management software for
agencies that could be something that's
interesting
yeah
hi Marin yes
the whole and and just a code
um so then I said we already have a
fairly stable underlying platform and
Tech stack at swvd getting that to
getting any changes to that would be
very very difficult and there's also a
lot of the compliance and regulatory
requirements that we need to take into
considerations that will make doing a
POC that affects our underlying systems
extremely difficult
we would prefer a plug-and-play or a
modular concept that being said if it's
about testing with the limited audience
it's about testing a limited audience
with the view of the initial POC likely
being conducted on your platform
that being said if it's targeted at
scaling there should be a view towards
fully integrating within FW at some
point
all right so I guess uh there will be
all for today webinars so before we end
like thanks everyone for your questions
and I hope that definitely you can gain
uh better credibility on FWD group and
also at the same time uh about the
program by Southern yep so before we end
uh we would like to uh extend our
gratitude and appreciation to Mark and
so learn and definitely each of you here
being part of this webinar to talk about
um the Innovations of insurance
inside uh in the in FW insurance and
definitely also mainly about the program
by sharing a lot of info and so through
the Q a sessions all right so
we will look forward to meet again uh in
the Futures event uh where we hope that
if you are interested to know more about
the
program definitely uh solo they leave
their relief his email address and also
the phone numbers so definitely you can
extend the conversation from there all
right so yep so we hope that the webinar
today uh can help you to spark new ideas
and also um
encourage you to join in the program and
to be part of the force to embrace the
transformative potential of insurance
industry all right so thank you and have
a nice day ahead yeah see you bye see
you soon hope to see you all in the next
couple weeks thanks for coming